### **CURRICULUM VITAE**

### PHYLLIS OBOTE-LUKORITO

Address: P.O. Box 23375-00625, Nairobi Kenya, Mobile: +254 722 672 165 E-mail: phyllis.lukorito@gmail.com, Nationality: Kenyan

#### **SUMMARY**

Experienced public health and corporate social responsibility executive; driven by integrity and strong ethical principles. A confident leader with a passion for smart business improvement with experience in advocacy, stakeholder engagement and compliance. Effectively communicates and reframes complex issues. Strong team player and leader; inspires and challenges others to achieve their potential.

#### AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Public health
- PPP management
- Sustainability
- Stakeholder Engagement
- Board and Team Leadership
- Compliance

- Strategic Planning and Integration
- Business Ethics
- Advocacy
- Social Behaviour change Implementation

### CAPABILITIES

- Over ten years of results based public health management with a passion in nutrition and health as a driver and catalyst for sustainable business.
- Stakeholder engagement and advocacy leveraging the scientific knowledge across the network to build sustainable relationships
- Evaluation of PPPs using Sustainable Transparent Effective Partnerships (STEP) methodology
- In depth understanding of innovation and renovation as a growth driver within the business by identifying gaps/opportunities within the Nutrition & Health sector.
- Health & Wellness education integrating nutrition education on lifestyle diseases prevention, management and care.
- Good communication skills and stake holder management on public affairs.
- Experienced in managing budgets and P&L

### **CAREER ACHIEVENMENTS**

2017: Championed partnership with the NGO to drive the social behaviour change in consumption of vegetable to improve nutrition status.

2016: Successful launch of the good breakfast campaign that involved local sourcing of rapeseed oil a key ingredient in manufacture of margarine and innovation of the product as part of the sustainable nutrition way of doing business

2015: Spearheaded the Nestle Nutrition Institute Africa to be recognized as a partner for Health Care Professional leading to the launch of the ESPGHAN course in East Africa which benefiting over 100 HCPs.

2011: Launched basic nutrition training course for all employees across the region achieving 90% coverage as part of Nestle commitment to driving NHW among employees

2008: Initiated close programming partnership with UNHCR, WFP, GTZ, AAH, SAVE UK and NCCK in areas of nutrition activities planning, development, conflict management, implementation and supervision.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

June 2018 to Present: Upfield Foods Limited

### **Head of Regulatory Affairs and Nutrition Africa**

Part of the transition team in the divestment of the spreads business out of Unilever. Working as part of the leadership team to ensure the new organization is set up for operations across Africa.

- Lead in giving expert regulatory guidance and recommendation in innovation & renovation of product portfolio across Africa.
- Lead overall compliance and initiate process improvement to ensure compliance in all aspect of relevant regulatory/government regulations
- Partner with category leaders in managing new and emerging regulations, access their impact to the business and execute plans to ensure continuous business operations
- Drive advocacy priorities by developing strategic influencing plans and collaborate with key internal stakeholders to align plans in support of product innovation.
- Ensure the products are aligned to the CODEX guidelines and local regulations as applicable.

March 2016 to May 2018: Unilever

### **Nutrition & Health Manager Africa**

Working with corporate leadership and teams to develop, implement, and communicate corporate Sustainable Nutrition efforts in the foods business. Work ranges from integrated strategic planning to project management, product innovation & renovation, strategic communication, and training: employee and stakeholder engagement, supply chain, waste management, energy, and facilities.

### Key Responsibilities:

- Shape and lead the regional Nutrition & Health Agenda for Foods Africa in strategic partnership with the Africa Category and Cluster leadership team.
- Work with business to unlock the role that responsible business can play in creating positive social impact by creating sustainable PPP that deliver impact and scale across the value chain.
- Lead and review Nutrition & Health advocacy strategy for key brands that ensures that key health sector stakeholders are involved.
- Design, execute and evaluate behaviour change programs that are scientifically based.
- Adapt and deploy centrally developed Nutrition communication approach and materials for both local "health influencers" (experts, health care professionals, NGOs, GOs, media, social networks and customers) and local consumers aimed at influencing local consumer behaviour to create demand for Unilever products in an effective way.
- Business partnering and stakeholder management which includes stakeholders such as Country Managers, Brand Development and Brand Building Directors and senior external stakeholders

May 2015 to February 2016: Nestlé Equatorial African Region

### **Medical & Scientific Affairs Manager**

Strategic partnership with Key Opinion Leaders in a highly regularized and legislated area of Infant Nutrition. My main responsibilities involved creating a platform for the business to showcase products, scientific knowledge to health care professionals and provide leadership to the Nestle Nutrition Institute Africa.

### Key Responsibilities:

- Develop strategy to engage medical fraternity in Science and Nutrition and popularizing scientific activities within health care fraternity.
- Provide timely scientific inputs and value-added responses to medical and nutrition queries from medical professionals, patient groups, government authorities and field force to strengthen relationship with these stakeholders
- Maintain and develop relationship with the Key Contacts from medical community to ensure a
  positive share of Voice for Nestle. Develop a set of Key Contacts as 'Speakers'/Script writers for
  Round Table conferences / Articles
- Continuously update medical/ product knowledge of field force and marketing group in coordination with the training team by devising and utilizing innovative methods of medical training.
- Build the image of the NNI in Africa as the Healthcare Professional's partner in advancing understanding of the science of nutrition

October 2010 to April 2015: Nestlé Equatorial African Region

## Regional NHW & Consumer Services Manager

World's Largest Nutrition Health & Wellness Company my primary goal was to translate both internally and externally. This involved strategic planning, documentation, activation of the NHW manifesto within the brands, to the consumers, employees and external stakeholders.

# Key responsibilities:

- Drive mindset change around Nutrition Health & Wellness in the region for the business units to embed NHW in the plans and Strategies ensuring this is embedded in the local Brand Essence
- Disseminate, influence and help implementation locally of the Company and SBU / GMB NHW Strategies
- Ensure the consumers have an active platform to reach Nestlé for assistance within EAR region; this is through consumer care lines, social media platforms and face to face consumer visits
- Organize internal activation to keep NHW top of mind
- Drive and own Market NHW Dashboard which supports external commitment to stakeholders on public health sensitive nutrients.

Jan 2010 to August 2010: Gertrude's Garden Children's Hospital

## **Head Hospital Nutritionist**

July 2007 to August 2008: CARE International in Kenya (Emergency & Refugee Operations Dadaab Refugee Camp)

**Infant & Young Child Feeding Nutritionist** 

Mar 2006- June 2007: Mulago National and referral Hospital (Kampala -Uganda) Chief Nutritionist (Burns' and Plastic Surgery Unit)

July 2005– Feb 2006: Center for Nutrition Education & Research (CENER)

**Nutritionist (Weight loss & Wellness)** 

#### **EDUCATION**

2008- 2009: United States International University-Africa, Nairobi.

# **Executive Master of Science in Organizational Development**

Part of the Transformational Leadership Programme

2002 -2005: Kenyatta University

# Bachelor of Science (Foods, Nutrition and Dietetics),

Baseline surveys: School age going children at risk of obesity in Nairobi

**Skills Training** 

2010: Pediatric Endocrinology Training Center Africa

**Certificate in Growth in Practice** 

2007: International Union of Health Promotion & Education

Certificate in Cardiovascular health promotion and chronic disease

**Epidemiology and management** 

2005: Stellenbosch University

Certificate in weight loss management and treatment

Assessing risk factors, prevention and the strategies employed

### **INTERESTS & HOBBIES**

Board games (Scrabble, Chess), Cooking, Hiking, Camping, Gyming, Swimming & Reading, Public health journals and self-improvement books

## <u>Referees</u>

Ms. Leah Kaguara Country Director Global Alliance For Improved Nutrition (GAIN) Wu Yi Plaza 4th Floor Block A8, Galana Road P.O Box 13733-00800, Nairobi

Mobile: +254 722 575 095 E-Mail: lkaguara@gainhealh.org

Ms. Agnes Kitololo Category Director Africa, Pepsico South Africa, 1 Simba Rd, Parkhaven,Boksburg 1459, South Africa

Mobile: +254 790 201 471

E-Mail: Agnes.Kitololo@pepsico.com

Ms. Alice A. Ojwang'
Nutrition and Dietetics Consultant
North West University-Centre of Excellence for Nutrition
11, Hoffman Street,
Building G16- Room 156
Potchefstroom, North West Province.
Republic of South Africa

Mobile: +27 60 929 4510 Email: ojwangaa@gmail.com